# Yueun Kim

▼ yueunkim.dev ☑ yk@yueunkim.dev ☑ Denver, CO

## **Summary**

I'm a full-stack software engineer with a passion for collaborating to solve challenging problems. I have experience with the JavaScript, Ruby, and Go ecosystems. Most recently, I created <u>Cascade</u> , an open-source containerized application deployment solution with automated observability built with Node.js/Express, OpenTelemetry, React, and Terraform CDK for TypeScript.

## **Experience**

#### 2022 – present

### **Creator, Software Engineer**

*Cascade* (https://try-cascade.github.io ☑)

- Created Cascade, an open-source containerized application deployment solution with built-in support for observability
- Streamlined the build and teardown processes of AWS infrastructure creation using Terraform CDK for TypeScript
- Built an NPM package for tracing instrumentation compatible with AWS Distro for OpenTelemetry Collector and AWS X-Ray
- Crafted a solution for visualizing the real-time data of resource creation statuses
- Designed an API server for communication with the AWS SDK
- Automated deployment using Docker (images, docker-compose)
- Authored a comprehensive technical case study on design decisions and challenges of building Cascade
- Collaborated with a remote team of 4 engineers across 3 timezones using agile workflow

#### 2021 - 2022

#### **Software Engineer**

Open-source web applications and Launch School experience

- Developed open-source software using Ruby, Node.js, Express, React, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, HTML/CSS, and more
- Selected projects:
  - Yarn Basket: a real-time webhook debugging tool with custom endpoints (Node.js, Express, Handlebars, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, DigitalOcean Droplet, Nginx, PM2)
  - The Shoppe: a database-backed e-commerce app (Node, React, MongoDB, Docker)
  - Flight Tracker: an SVG map for filtering and viewing airline routes (React, Docker)

2012 - 2021

Performed and instructed piano, and organized operations of an international piano festival

## Skills

Backend
Node.js, Express, Ruby, Go,
PostgreSQL, MongoDB, RESTful
APIs

#### Frontend

JavaScript, TypeScript, React, Next.js, HTML/CSS, Tailwind CSS

## Tooling

Git/GitHub, Docker, Linux, Bash, OpenTelemetry, AWS (S3, SQS, EC2, ECS), Terraform

#### **Education**

**Rice University,** Master of Music, Piano Chamber Music

**Northwestern University,** Master of Music, Piano Performance and Pedagogy

**Eastman School of Music,** Bachelor of Music, Piano Performance